Inventory of the Fight for Freedom Committee records
Hoover Institution Archives
Fight for Freedom Committee records
1940-1942
58027
Hoover Institution Archives
5 manuscript boxes, 1 oversized box (2.0 linear feet)
Correspondence, memoranda, press releases, pamphlets, clippings, and printed matter, relating to interventionist and non-interventionist movements in the United States during World War II, the America First Committee, and the activities of Charles Lindbergh and Herbert Hoover in the non-interventionist movement.
Fight for Freedom Committee.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1958.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
Private organization lobbying for American intervention in World War II.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, memoranda, press releases, pamphlets, clippings, and printed matter, relating to interventionist and non-interventionist movements in the United States during World War II, the America First Committee, and the activities of Charles Lindbergh and Herbert Hoover in the non-interventionist movement.
America First Committee.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Lindbergh, Charles Augustus, 1902-1974.; United States--Neutrality.; World War, 1939-1945--United States.
- Miscellaneous, 1941 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Fight for Freedom Inc. - Press release, 1941 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- Fight for Freedom Inc. - Contribution lists, 1941 (Box-folder 1: 3-4)
- Fight for Freedom Inc. - Correspondence and press releases, 1941 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- Fight for Freedom Inc. - Correspondence, forms etc., 1941 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- Fight for Freedom Inc. - Form letters etc., 1941 (Box-folder 1: 7)
- Miscellaneous, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 1)
- Propaganda - pamphlets, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 2)
- General propaganda, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 3)
- Newletters - notices, etc., 1941 (Box-folder 2: 4)
- Duplicates, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 5)
- Press releases, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 6)
- Labels- Rex Stout, 1941 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- General information, 1941 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- Press releases and correspondence, 1941 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- Rex Stout smear, American Forum of the Air, 1941 March 28 (Box-folder 3: 4)
- Miscellaneous publications, 1941 (Box-folder 3: 5)
- General propaganda, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 1)
- Fight for Freedom meetings, congresses, notices, agenda, etc., 1941 (Box-folder 4: 2)
- General propaganda, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 3)
- Advertising, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 4)
- Dr. W. M. Agar, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 5)
- Herbert Agar, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 6)
- Workers Defense, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 7)
- Foreign Division, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 8)
- Addresses, speeches, articles, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 9)
- Propaganda, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 10)
- Labor News Service publications, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 11)
- Committee lists, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 12)
- American Unity League, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 13)
- Union Now, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 14)
- National Unity League, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 15)
- Friends of Democracy, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 16)
- American Youth for Freedom, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 17)
- Clearing house for youth groups, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 18)
- Citizens for Victory, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 19)
- Associated League for a Declared War, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 20)
- Miscellaneous, 1941 (Box-folder 5: 1)
- Oversized posters, magazines, newspapers, etc., 1941 (Box 6)